Hammad Ali Khan Data Engineer

Contact

Address

Karachi, SD, 75850

Phone

923362148088

E-mail

hammad4898@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hak-dev/

WWW

https://hak-code.github.io/ hak.github.io/

Skills

AWS

Very Good

Python

Very Good

<u>ElasticSearch</u>

Very Good

Nodeis

Good

Java

Good

Algorithms

Good

I am interested in research and development in the field of Python, Java, and Node.js. Currently working as a Senior Software Engineer at EIX Enterprise Information Xperts. The main focus is on Data Engineering implementation on cloud infrastructure mainly AWS. Using concepts of big data involving transformation, ML, query, analytics, and reporting. Using technologies to build data lake and data warehouse for driving business insights for customer valuable data.

Work History

2022-03 -Current

Senior Software II Engineer

Airlift Technologies (Startup)

- Working on back-end featuring new API, unit testing, CI/CD pipelines
- Working closely on observability of AWS infrastructure involving ELK stack, cloud lens, X-Rays, NewRelic, cloudwatch etc
- Sharing knowledge with teammates about good practices, scalability, code coverage, testing and good coding standards

2021-11 -

Senior Software Engineer

2022-02

Systems Limited, deployed on Regeneron

 Worked with product manager of Regeneron for exploring new open source technologies

2020-11 -2021-11

Senior Software Engineer

EIX (Enterprise Integration Xperts), Karachi, Pakistan Deployed on a US-based startup Tenovos

- Worked closely with other product owners, development teams, and infrastructure specialists to deliver high-availability solutions for digital asset management applications
- Anchoring team, code review, architecting, implementation, and performance improvement.
- Documented software design, detected faults, troubleshooting, and other vital system component
- Team involve building new features for clients like Google, Amazon fuse, Canadian Tyre Corporation to name a few

Analytics and Visualisation

Good

Serverless

Good

ETL

Good

2019-10 -2020-10

Lead Software Engineer

REON ENERGIES, Karachi, Pakistan

- Lead engineering team, requirement gathering from Product Head, technical analysis, and implementation
- Translated customer and system requirements into robust software design with a test-driven approach
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations
- Implemented and adopted cloud technologies and best practices for automation, configuration, monitoring, and platform scalability

2018-10 -2019-10

Senior Software Engineer

Zaavya, Karachi, Pakistan

A startup building an MDM(Master Data Management) data platform for a US-based client Neiman Marcus. The platform is focused on data processing provided deep relations of eCommerce identities. My role includes the following:

- Requirement gathering from company CEO, involve in designing solution and data modeling
- Implementation of product workflow, API designing, and research on new technologies
- Working closely with Neiman's team with infrastructure implementation
- Implement failure handling and retry mechanism on influx ingest of data

2017-03 -2018-10

Data Engineer

Inbox Business Technology, Karachi, Pakistan

A startup for building smart product based on machine learning and data sciences. My role include following:

- Generated detailed studies on potential third-party data handling solutions, verifying compliance with internal needs and stakeholder requirements
- Analyzed complex data and identified anomalies, trends and risks to provide useful insights to improve internal controls

- Developed, implemented, supported and maintained data analytics protocols, standards and documentation
- Lead the REON IoT project for implementation of software(real-time monitoring system) on AWS cloud

2016-02 -2017-02

Game Developer

Tenpearls, Karachi, Pakistan

Gameplan8 is a game development depart of TenPearls. Where I love to build complex game logic targeting cross-platform devices mainly iOS and Android. Having deep experience on Unity3D along with cocos2D

Education

2011-07 -2015-12 **Bachelor of Science: Computer Science**

FAST-NU - Karachi

Accomplishments

 Letter of Appreciation from REON Energies for delivering high quality Web and Mobile application for data platform SPARK. Providing real-time analytics and alarms for mission-critical services.

Cloud Skills

Have a good experience of following cloud technologies:

- Processing services includes EC2, Lambda, ECS
- Databases include postgres, dynamodb(AWS), mongodb, neptune(AWS), timestream(AWS), Aurora(AWS)
- IoT services like lot Core, lot Device Management, lot Events, lot Greengrass, lot Fleet. Protocols like MQTT, Kafka broker.
- Caching service Elasticache (Redis)
- Orchestration service AWS Step Functions, Airflow



- Other services include SNS, SQS, SES, Cloudwatch, X-Rays, API-Gateway
- Search engine Elasticsearch (ELK stack elastic cloud)
- Cloud infra development using AWS SAM with codepipeline and codecommit for CI/CD